<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>emacs on hangaroundtheweb</title>
    <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in emacs on hangaroundtheweb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:57:51 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://hangaroundtheweb.com/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Playing Music in Spacemacs with EMMS</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/playing-music-in-spacemacs-with-emms/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 02 Jul 2020 00:57:51 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/playing-music-in-spacemacs-with-emms/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking about playing songs inside Spacemacs for quite a while, so that I don&amp;rsquo;t have to leave my favorite editor for just playing music. After a small exploration I found out that all I need is to enable EMMS inside Spacemacs.
Spacemacs Spacemacs is a community-driven Emacs distribution. It is a new way to experience Emacs with a sophisticated and polished set-up focused on ergonomics, mnemonics and consistency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Using nvm with Spacemacs</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/using-nvm-with-spacemacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jun 2020 21:01:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/using-nvm-with-spacemacs/</guid>
      <description>nvm is a version manager for Node.js, designed to be installed per-user, and invoked per-shell. nvm works on any POSIX-compliant shell (sh, dash, ksh, zsh, bash), in particular on these platforms: Unix, Mac OS, and Windows WSL. But most of the times, it is not properly identified by eshell in Spacemacs. Recently I found out a package called nvm.el by Johan Andersson.
Let&amp;rsquo;s walk you through how you can use nvm to choose different Node.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setting up Prettier on Spacemacs</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/setting-up-prettier-on-spacemacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 30 May 2020 03:59:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/setting-up-prettier-on-spacemacs/</guid>
      <description>What is Spacemacs? Spacemacs is a community-driven Emacs distribution. It is a new way to experience Emacs with a sophisticated and polished set-up focused on ergonomics, mnemonics and consistency.
What is Prettier? Prettier is an opinionated code formatter which supports many languages and integrates with most editors. It can be installed through npm. It is recommended to install prettier globally in your system so that your editor integrates it properly and can be even made to auto formatted while saving your files.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mind maps in Spacemacs</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/mind-maps-in-spacemacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2019 18:06:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/mind-maps-in-spacemacs/</guid>
      <description>This post is the second in the series of posts called PlantUML in Spacemacs. In this post we are going to see how we can create awesome Mind maps in Spacemacs using PlantUML. Mind map diagrams is the new feature recently rolled out in PlantUML and they are still in the beta* stage.
And you will find only minimal documentation in the official site related to mind map diagrams. This post gives you some additional bonus information such as adding colors to your mind map, creating high resolution mind maps and so on.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>PlantUML in Spacemacs</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/plantuml-in-spacemacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2019 03:04:02 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/plantuml-in-spacemacs/</guid>
      <description>This article is the first in the series of articles about including and using PlantUML in Spacemacs to do some amazing things. In this article we will see how to setup PlantUML in Spacemacs and use it. In the upcoming posts we will see some advanced usage of PlantUML and some awesome stuff you can do with it.
Spacemacs Spacemacs is a community-driven Emacs distribution. It is a new way to experience Emacs with a sophisticated and polished set-up focused on ergonomics, mnemonics and consistency.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>A guide to create tmux like Custom Layouts in Spacemacs</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/a-guide-to-create-tmux-like-custom-layouts-in-spacemacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Jun 2019 05:54:08 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/a-guide-to-create-tmux-like-custom-layouts-in-spacemacs/</guid>
      <description>Coming from a vim world with tmux, I had really missed the multiple split window layout in Spacemacs. But after knowing how to define custom layouts this seemed to be an easy exercise for me.
So I thought, I should write a blog post about it to help others setup awesome layouts and workspaces with Spacemacs.
Some Terminology Here I want to make some clarifications on the terminology surrounding vim, tmux and Emacs on windows, layouts, panes and buffers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to use Thesaurus from Spacemacs</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/how-to-use-thesaurus-from-spacemacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Jun 2019 02:28:03 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/how-to-use-thesaurus-from-spacemacs/</guid>
      <description>In this tutorial, we will see how we can integrate the Merriam Webster Thesaurus in to Spacemacs. Having a thesaurus by your side while writing, is really a productive thing. Since you don&amp;rsquo;t have to lookup every time the alternative word you want to use and that too integrating with your favorite editor is definitely a feather in your cap.
For this we are going to install an awesome package from Ag Ibragimov called mw-thesaurus.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Refactor your Javascript like a Pro with js2-refactor</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/refactor-your-javascript-like-a-pro-with-js2-refactor/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Jul 2017 03:25:15 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/refactor-your-javascript-like-a-pro-with-js2-refactor/</guid>
      <description>In this article i will show you how to use the js2-refactor tool in Spacemacs which is a community built version of Emacs using Space key as the leader key. Table of Contents  1. Refactor your Javascript like a Pro with js2-refactor  1.1. Installation - Emacs 1.2. Installation - Spacemacs 1.3. Usage 1.4. Refactorings  1.4.1. js2r-expand-array 1.4.2. js2r-expand-object 1.4.3. js2r-expand-function 1.4.4. js2r-extract-function 1.4.5. js2r-extract-method 1.4.6. js2r-extract-var 1.4.7. js2r-contract-array 1.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
