<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>quotes on hangaroundtheweb</title>
    <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/tags/quotes/</link>
    <description>Recent content in quotes on hangaroundtheweb</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 23:45:42 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://hangaroundtheweb.com/tags/quotes/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Classical quotations and words of wisdom on managing software</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/classical-quotations-and-words-of-wisdom-on-managing-software/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Jul 2018 23:45:42 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/classical-quotations-and-words-of-wisdom-on-managing-software/</guid>
      <description>Managing Software - Words of Wisdom Software project management is an art and science of planning and leading software projects. It is a sub-discipline of project management in which software projects are planned, implemented, monitored and controlled. These words of wisdom are the outcome of multi-role viewpoint on software development. There is no ranking for better practices. But what really matters is to apply these practices where they make sense and where the users can benefit the most.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Nine Illuminating Quotes on Debugging</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/nine-illuminating-quotes-on-debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jul 2018 22:54:06 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/nine-illuminating-quotes-on-debugging/</guid>
      <description>Nine Illuminating Quotes on Debugging Here we present you a list of quotes about debugging programs by renowned developers and programmers from around the world.
Quote #1  Of all my programming bugs, 80% are syntax errors. Of the remaining 20%, 80% are trivial logical errors. Of the remaining 4%, 80% are pointer errors. And the remaining 0.4% are hard. – Marc Donner, IBM Watson Research Center
 Quote #2  It takes three times the effort to find and fix bugs in system test than when done by the developer.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Six Sensible Quotes on User Interface</title>
      <link>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/six-sensible-quotes-on-user-interface/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 20 Jul 2018 18:34:41 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://hangaroundtheweb.com/posts/six-sensible-quotes-on-user-interface/</guid>
      <description>Six Sensible Quotes on User Interface Quote #1  The Principle of Least Astonishment Make a user interface as consistent and as predictable as possible.
  Quote #2  A program designed for inputs from people is usually stressed beyond the breaking point by computer-generated inputs. – Dennis Ritchie, Bell Labs
  Quote #3  Twenty percent of all input forms filled out by people contain bad data. – Vic Vyssotsky, Bell Labs</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
